A Guide to the Henry Iddings Family Collection, 1810-1900
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Henry Iddings Family Collection, 1810-1900
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms2013-021
0.5 cu. ft. 1 box, 1 oversize folder
This collection includes 19th century personal papers (correspondence, legal document, land-related materials, and tax receipts) from the Henry Iddings Family of Floyd County, Virginia.
Henry Iddings Family
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The Henry Iddings Family Collection was acquired by Special Collections in February 2013.
Biographical Note
The Iddings family immigrated to America from Radnorshire, Wales ,and first settled in Chester County, Pennsylvania. James Iddings is the first Iddings found in a record for the area now known as Floyd County. Henry Iddings was likely James Iddings nephew.
Henry Iddings was born in Pennsylvania in 1762. In 1789, he married Abigail Richardson. They had eleven children between 1790 and 1817. Iddings died in Virginia in 1854. More information about Iddings and his descendants is available in the collection.
Scope and Content
This collection consists of personal papers from the Henry Iddings family of Floyd County, Virginia. Papers include tax tickets and receipts, land grants, deed, estate settlement papers, correspondence, promissory notes, and other ephemera. Materials date from approximately 1810-1900. Prior to 1830, the current Floyd County was part of Montgomery County. Some early documents may refer to Montgomery County. Also included is a family produced genealogy of the descendants of Henry Iddings and his wife, Abigail Richardson.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged alphabetically by material type.
Index Terms
Persons:
Iddings, Henry, 1762-1854
Family Names:
Henry Iddings Family
Subjects:
Civil War; Floyd County (Va.); Local/Regional History and Appalachian South; Montgomery County (Va.); United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865
Contents List
- Correspondence, 1837-1900 (Box-folder 1-1)
- Contracts and Legal Documents-Copies, 1810-1899 (Box-folder 1-2)
- Contracts and Legal Documents-Copies, undated (Box-folder 1-3)
- Civil War Oaths, 1865 (Box-folder 1-4)
- Descendants of Henry Iddings and Abby Richardson (Genealogy), 1996 (Box-folder 1-5)
- Land Grants, 1819-1820, 1841, 1843 (Folder 1)
- Land and Survey Documents, 1836-1900 (Box-folder 1-6)
- Photographs-Copies (Box-folder 1-7)
- Receipts and Promissory Notes, 1814-1893 (Box-folder 1-8)
- Receipts and Promissory Notes, undated (Box-folder 1-9)
- Tax Receipts, 1834-1899 (Box-folder 1-10)